Kristopher L. Lucas MT(ASCP)

1412 Briarhaven Trail Brookhaven, Ga 30319 Phone: (404) 550-5082 E-mail: klucas72@hotmail.com

QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelors of Science degrees in Medical Technology and Network Communications and Management with twenty years of laboratory and IT experience in diverse facilities. Expertise in technical and management in a diverse environment. Areas of expertise include:

Windows Server Administrator Cisco Routers and switches

Full Stack Web Development Medical Lab (LIS) instrument interfaces VMWare vCenter Software Linux Redhat Server Administrator

Lab Info System Interface Specialist ASTM/HL7 Knowledge

CERTIFICATION

National Registry

Project Management Certificate

Project Meb Development Certificate

American Society for Clinical Pathology #03628940

University of Georgia

July, 2017

Georgia Institute of Technology

July 2021

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Network Administrator Maintained, monitored and performed administrative tasks for Small

Business Servers for clients in various environments. Knowledge of various transmission and routing protocols such as OSPF and RIP.

Software Implementation Specialist/Consultant

Specialist

Deployed and set up software database packages on customer network. Performed customer oriented training after deployment and provided post installation support for any user questions or concerns

Full Stack Web Developer Created and developed web applications for public and private use.

https://klucas72.github.io/Portfolio/

https://github.com/klucas72

Accomplishments:

HISTORY

Software Systems Technical Immucor, Inc.

2013 to present

- Analyzed and troubleshot MiaFora Servers for configuration network communications issues. Worked with international customers resolving their issues.
- Installed software using SQL for database, IIS, Redhat OS configurations
- Trained customers on the use and maintenance of LIS interface software.
- Project manager for setting up and installing software database package on customer networks.
- Setup and configured instrument interfaces (LIS) for lab instruments to talk to customer laboratory information systems.

Network Administrator

Alpha Group/Altair Advanced Ind. 2012 to 2013 *Accomplishments:*

- administered domain policies, set permissions, roles, and access to various network resources. Installed complete wireless network for customers.
- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for the domain as well as set up and maintained network servers.

Network Administrator /Consultant

Johnny on the Spot, Inc./TophTech Consulting 2010 to 2012 *Accomplishments:*

- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for clients. Set up and maintained network servers for various businesses.
- Created and designed networks for small businesses including routers, switches, and wifi access points.

Supervisor, Blood Bank Transfusion Medicine Program

Emory Crawford Long Hospital, Laboratory 2007 to 2011 *Accomplishments:*

- Directed and maintained quality control maintenance for department. Reviewed monthly QC and performed corrective action as needed.
- Supervised and assisted personnel in training, performing testing, selection of products, and distribution of products to patients.

Tissue Bank Coordinator, Blood & Tissue Services

Children's Healthcare of Atlanta, Laboratory 2005 to 2007 *Accomplishments*:

- Created, developed, and implemented the Tissue LIS from Blood Bank portion of the Misys Laboratory Information System.
- Implemented centralization of all tissue as required by JCAHO, FDA, and related regulatory agencies.

U.S. Naval Officer

Naval Medical Center, San Diego, California

1996 –1999

Network Admin/Engineer

Toph Tech Consulting *Accomplishments:*

2011 to present

- administered domain policies, set permissions, roles, and access to various network resources. Installed complete wireless network for organization.
- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for the domain as well as set up and maintained network servers.

EDUCATION

Network Communications and Management DeVry University, Atlanta, Ga 2007-2012 Medical Technology Indiana State University, Terre Haute, IN 1991–1995